Guide to the Abraham Epstein Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Abraham Epstein Papers,
1918-1945.
Epstein, Abraham, 1892-1942.
ca. 50,000 items (86 boxes, 2 cmi boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078739
Biographical Note
Research Director, Pennsylvania Commission on Old Age Pensions, 1918-1921 and 1923-1927; Executive Secretary, American Association for Social Security, 1927-1942.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, minutes, lists, reports, financial records, and printed materials of Abraham Epstein. The personal and business papers relate to his fight on behalf of Social Security and old age pensions.
Subjects
Pennsylvania--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.; Social security--United States.; Old age pensions.; Older people--Economic conditions.; Social problems.; Pennsylvania Commission of Old Age Pensions.; Social reformers.
Access Restrictions
Boxes 2-86 of this collections are are located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1950 M-50 Epstein, Mrs. Abraham Gift
- Contents List
  - Adams Jane--Correspondence (October 1929-June 1935) (Box 1)
  - Advisory Commission to the Council of National: Defense Reports, etc. (July 194O-.January 1941) (Box 1)
  - Alabama--Correspondence (April 1929-June 1938) (Box 1)
  - Amalgamated Bank of Now York--Correspondence (June 1931-January 1952) (Box 1)
  - American Child, published by the National Child Labor Committee., N.Y. City (November 1931-April 1941) (Box 1)
  - America. Association for Economic Freedom, Wash., D.C.--Correspondence, declaration, etc. (October 1937-February 1938) (Box 1)
  - American Association for Social Security: (Box 2)
    - Appeals for money--Correspondence, etc. (May 1931-November 1942) (Box 2)
    - Appeals foundations--Correspondence, etc. (January 1932-0ct. 1935) (Box 2)
    - Bill--"A State Old Age Assistance Bill" (Box 2)
    - Commended in correspondence (June 1932-April 1941) (Box 2)
    - Comments on work & N.Y. old age pension bills (March 1926-April 1931) (Box 2)
    - Constitution: (Box 2)
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Suggested draft (Box 2)
    - Cooperative struggle for existence--Correspondence, announcement, etc. (December 1941-September 1942) (Box 2)
    - Luce's Press Clipping Bureau--Correspondence (June 1931-June 1943) (Box 2)
    - Nice letters responding to appeals, etc. (October-November 1941) (Box 2)
    - Organization--Beginning--Correspondence, minutes, etc. (January-December 1927) (Box 2)
    - Press release (January 1957-November 1958) (Box 3)
    - Press release (February 1959-0ct. 1940) (Box 3)
    - Publicity--Correspondence (April 1941-January 1942) (Box 3)
    - Requests for information:
      - 1 (May - December 1928) (Box 3)
      - 2 (January- February 1929) (Box 3)
      - 3 (March - April 1929) (Box 3)
      - 4 (May- October 1929) (Box 3)
      - 5 (August- October 1929) (Box 3)
  - A.A.S.S.: (Box 4)
    - Advisory Council--Correspondence (October 1927-November 1933) (Box 4)
    - Advisory Com. on Social Insurance--Correspondence, lists, etc.:
      - 1 (June 1935) (Box 4)
      - 2 (July 1933-December 1940) (Box 4)
    - Board of Directors:
      - Invitations to meetings: (Box 4)
      - (January 1937-December 1938) (Box 4)
      - (January 1939-November 1940) (Box 4)
      - Minutes (October 1935-December 1940) (Box 4)
    - Executive Committee meetings--Correspondence, minutes, etc.: (Box 5)
      - 1 (September 1929-December 1930) (Box 5)
      - 2 (January 1931-Apr1 l932) (Box 5)
      - Minutes, agenda, etc. (March 1927-May 1933) (Box 5)
    - Social security (monthly):
      - Free mailing lists: (Box 5)
      - 1 (March 1933-NUv. 1936) (Box 5)
      - 2 (February 1937-November 1941) (Box 5)
  - American Council on Public Affairs. Schnapper, Morris B.: (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, pamphlets, etc. (December 1937-November 1941) (Box 6)
  - American Federation of Labor:
    - Correspondence, draft, etc. (November 1929-5ept. 1942) (Box 6)
    - Maurer, James H. -- Correspondence (February 1927) (Box 6)
    - Pres. Green, William-- Correspondence, bills, etc. (August 1931-March 1936) (Box 6)
  - American Mercury--Correspondence (November 1930-February 1932) (Box 6)
  - American various assns.--National conferences--Program (May-December 1933) (Box 6)
  - Appeal for charity--C1ippings, pamphlets, etc. (December 1924-February 1929) (Box 6)
  - Argentina--Pensions, correspondence, etc. (1921-June 1927) (Box 7)
  - Arizona--Correspondence (September 1930-July 1933) (Box 7)
  - Arkansas--Correspondence (February 1929-Feg. 1940) (Box 7)
  - Associated Silk Workers. Matthews, Joseph E.--Correspondence (January1930-February1932) (Box 7)
  - Associations of social work, workers, consumers, universities, churches, etc.:
    - Correspondence lists, etc. (September1928-April 1941) (Box 7)
  - Austria--Acts, etc. (December1906-December 1924) (Box 7)
  - Australia--Pamphlets, regulation, table, forms, correspondence (l908-December1926) (Box 7)
  - Bardwell, Francis, Bureau of Old Age Assistance, MA.-Correspondence (April 1931-April 1942) (Box 8)
  - Barkin, Solomon--Correspondence (May-July 1933) (Box 8)
  - Battle, George G.--Correspondence (March 1931-March 1932) (Box 8)
  - Belgium--Bul., pamphlet (1925) (Box 8)
  - Billikopf, Dr. Jacob--Correspondence(January1928-1930/1931-January1942) (Box 8)
  - Bills 1931--Drafts--Arkansas, Conn., Mich., Ohio (Box 8)
  - Blossom, Frederick A. Correspondence, etc (January 1932-March 1942) (Box 8)
  - Bradon, Jack. The Truth About Weekly Industrial Insurance) (magazine), Chicago, Ill.—Corerspondence (June 1933-April 1937) (Box 8)
  - Brazil--Décret No. 4,682 (Janvier 1923) (Box 8)
  - Broadeasting--WNYC (February1938) (Box 8)
  - Brookwood, Inc., A School for.Progressive Labor Education --Correspondence, etc. (October1927-March 1936) (Box 8)
  - Bulgaria-regulat1ons, etc. (March 1906-June 1924) (Box 8)
  - Burlingham, C. C., N.Y.City--Correspondence, etc. (March 1929-November1939) (Box 8)
  - Caldwell, Helen E .Irving, N.J.-- Correspondence. (August1928-January1930) (Box 9)
  - California--Correspondence (February l939-February1942) (Box 9)
  - CaliSocial Welfare Dept.-- Correspondence. (January1929-December1938) (Box 9)
  - Canada--Correspondence (December1929-January1942) (Box 9)
  - Canada. Dept. of Labour. Government. Annuities Branch--Report, Correspondence, etc. (March 1936-April 1938) (Box 9)
  - Canada Toronto. Cohen, J.L. -- Correspondence. (April 1927-November1928) (Box 9)
  - Cartoons, drawings, etc.--Old age pensions (February 1932-July 1935) (Box 9)
  - Chamberlin, Joseph P ~ Columbia University--Correspondence, (1928-1936) (Box 9)
  - Chile--Articles (1924) (Box 9)
  - Christian Social Justice Fund. Gilman, Elizabeth--Correspondence, (January 28-December 31)(January'32-July'38) (Box 9)
  - Christmas appeal--Clippings, etc. (Dee.1930) (Box 10)
  - Clark, ProJane, Perry. The rise of a new federalism--Correspondence, (July 1937-June 1938) (Box 10)
  - Cochran, Edwin Paul-- Correspondence (September1939-January1941) (Box 10)
  - Cogswell, Edmund S Extent of old age dependency (November-December 1926) (Box 10)
  - Cohen, Wilbur H. See: S.S.B. (Box 10)
  - Colorado--Correspondence (March 1938-August 1940) (Box 10)
  - Colorado Denver—Com. and general correspondence (July 1931-September1938) (Box 10)
  - Columbia University. Seager, Henry R - Correspondence. (February1930) (Box 10)
  - Connecticut--Correspondence, etc. (February1934-June 1940) (Box 10)
  - Conn, Commission on Old Age Pensions. Meeker, Royal-- Correspondence.(June 1931-August 1934) (Box 10)
  - Conn. Com. for Old Age Security: (Box 10)
  - Correspondence., etc. (June 1934-October1935) (Box 10)
  - Minutes (February1936-January1935) (Box 10)
  - Conn. Federation of Labor. Egan, John J.-- Correspondence. (March'30-September '41 (Box 10)
  - Czechoslovakia—Regulations (December 192l) (Box 10)
  - Delaware--Correspondence, etc. (February1929-September19S6) (Box 11)
  - Denmark--Notifications (June 1922-February1925) (Box 11)
  - Devine, Dr. Edward T -- Correspondence. (January1932-May 1937) (Box 11)
  - Dies Com.--Amer. Youth Cong. rebuffed by Epstein, A.—Correspondence (October-December'31 (Box 11)
  - Dill-Connery bill 1932 & l934-- Correspondence. (February’32-May'34) in 4 Folders. (Box 11)
  - Douglas, ProPaul H., University of Chicago -- Correspondence. (January ‘29-January ‘42) (Box 11)
  - duPont, Alfred I., Wilmington, Del.-- Correspondence. (October'3O-June ‘36) (Box 11)
  - The Eagle magazine (September1922 &December 1923)--Correspondence, clippings, etc. (July '33-September'37) (Box 12)
  - Eag1es, Fraternal Order of --Bulletins, Correspondence, etc. (April ‘22-November ’27) (Box 12)
  - Elias, Harry L. - Correspondence. (February 1931-August 1933) (Box 12)
  - Emergency Work Bureau--Correspondence, payroll sheets, etc. (December ’30-October '35) (Box 12)
  - Epstein, A.: (Box 13)
    - Articles (September 1923-?) in 4 Folders. (Box 13)
    - Correspondence (July 1950-1939) in 6 Folders. (Box 13)
    - Biographical materials (Box 13)
    - Biography by Preo, Fred L. (Box 13)
    - Biography &. Comment by Leonard, Oscar (February 1938) (Box 14)
    - Centennial Observance of the 100th Anniversary of Epstein's birth. (Correspondence and printed materials, 1992) (Box 14)
    - Helping far immigration visa: (Box 14)
    - Guigui, Albert--Correspondence, (February-April 1942) (Box 14)
    - Wadler, Arnold (September '40-December '41) (Box 14)
    - Rager, Dr. Fritz--Correspondence, etc. (April '38-November ‘41) (Box 14)
    - Personal correspondence (February 1927-June 1932) in 2 Folders. (Box 14)
    - Radio ta1ks--Correspondence, (October 1936-December 1940) (Box 14)
    - Research--Cards, clippings. (Box 14)
    - Speeches &lecture series--Perry & Wise, Inc.--Correspondence, lists, news releases, etc. (November'37-June '38) (Box 14)
    - Syllabi for (Comparative) Social Security courses (1941-1942) (Box 14)
    - Speaking endangerments--Correspondence, etc. (October '33-December '37) in 6 fo1ders. (Box 15)
    - Speaking engagements--Correspondence, etc. (January'33-May '39) in 2 Folders. (Box 16)
    - Western lecture tours, 1936 & 1937 in 5 Folders. (Box 16)
    - The Challenge of the aged--Correspondence, etc. ('28-September'42) in 4 Folders (Box 17)
    - Insecurity: a challenge to America (l936-July 1942) in 4 Folders. (Box 17)
    - The Insurance Racket, articles (1930-1934) in 5 Folders. (Box 18)
    - N.Y.U. term papers by his student.(June 1940-January 1942) in 4 Folders. (Box 18)
  - Epstein, Mrs. Abraham--Correspondence, (December 1937-May 1938) (Box 19)
  - Epstein, the Abraham Testimonial Com. --Financial statements, appeals, etc. (January 1942-February 1943) (Box 19)
  - Evening Sun, Baltimore. Fitzgerald, Stephen E.—Corresponence (January ’37-October ‘40 (Box 19)
  - Federated Press—releases in I (Box 19)
  - Federated Press--Releases on old age pensions, labor movement, etc. (July 1927-June 1934) (Box 19)
  - Florida--Correspondence (February 1928-October 1939) (Box 19)
  - Flynn, John T. --Correspondence against Epstein's militancy, statements about several state and associations, etc. (February '39-May ‘40) (Box 19)
  - Foreign correspondence (January 1930-June 1941) in 4 Folders. (Box 19)
  - Foundations. The Thrift & Security Foundation. Fell, Herbert N.--Correspondence (August 1937-October 1937) (Box 20)
  - Foundations, Philanthropic--Pamphlets, reports, clippings, & Correspondence, (1930-May 1942) (Box 20)
  - France:
    - Act (July 1909), rapports, bul. (1923-September 1925) (Box 20)
    - Pamphlets, etc. (1900-Mars 1925) in 2 Folders. (Box 20)
  - France, Clemens J. --Correspondence (March 1941-April 1943) (Box 20)
  - Fur industry--Charity chest--Correspondence( etc. (I1ay 1929-January 1940) (Box 20)
  - Gage, Margaret--Correspondence (February 1935-June 1943) (Box 21)
  - Gale, Zona's story Lights out (1932-1934) (Box 21)
  - General Welfare Act--Correspondence, etc. (September 1937-January 1940) (Box 21)
  - Georgia--Correspondence (February 1929-April 1940) (Box 21)
  - Germany--Pamphlet & correspondence (July-September 1921) (Box 21)
  - Gilbert, Mart & E. Albert, Philadelphia, Pa. --Correspondence, (February 1936-May 1937) (Box 21)
  - Glassberg, Benjamin--Federated Jewish Charities, etc. (Box 21)
  - Glassberg, Benjamin--Correspondence (January 1928-January 1935) (Box 21)
  - Great Britain: (Box 22)
    - Bibl., etc. (1925 etc.) (Box 22)
    - Industrial welfare in England: (Box 22)
    - Pamphlets, magazines (1999-1925) (Box 22)
  - Bournville--Pamphlets, etc. (May '06-September'25) (Box 22)
  - Pamphlets, rept., & correspondence, (1908-June 1925) (Box 22)
  - Greece--Acts, decrees, etc. (1924-1925) (Box 22)
  - Haber, ProWilliam, Mich.--Correspondence (December 1935-February 1942) (Box 23)
  - Harmon, William E.--Correspondence, & a plan for old age & investment protection (May-June 1927) (Box 23)
  - Hawaii--Correspondence (March 1937-April 1939) (Box 23)
  - Hitler, Adolf--Public speeches--Extracts (10 February 1933-1 September 1939) (Box 23)
  - Hogue, Dr. Richard W.--Correspondence (June 1954-January 1941) in 2 Folders (Box 23)
  - Home for Aged and Infirm Hebrews, NY City—Correspondence, suggested program (February 1932-1939) (Box 23)
  - Hurst, Fennie--Correspondence (February 1934-November 1935) (Box 23)
  - Hyde, Albert Alexander, Wichita, Kan.--Correspondence, etc. (January '29-February '35) (Box 23)
  - Iceland--Act, the General Old Age Pension (9 July 1909) (Box 24)
  - Idaho--Correspondence, etc. (February 1929-May 1938) (Box 24)
  - Illinois:
    - Correspondence (March 1934-November 1941) (Box 24)
    - The British Old People's Home (under the auspices of the Daughters of the British Empire in the Middle Western States). Adams, Pres. Julie Cooke--Correspondence, etc. (January 1934-May 1937) (Box 24)
    - The American Legislators' Assn.--Correspondence (March 1931-June 1935) (Box 24)
    - Chicago--Correspondence, etc. (February 1934-Qct. 1941) in 2 Folders. (Box 24)
    - Commission on Old Age Pensions-Correspondence. (January 1932-December 1932) (Box 24)
    - Committee for Old Age Security,-Lists, correspondence(March 1933) (Box 24)
  - Imberman, A. A.-Correspondence (September 1937-January 1942) (Box 24)
  - India. The Indian witness vol. LVI no.42 (20 October 1926) (Box 24)
  - Indiana--Correspondence (January 1930-February 1942) (Box 25)
  - Insurance:
    - Insurance Law Revision--Draft, Correspondence, (January 1939-June 1941) (Box 25)
    - Pamphlets, articles, etc. (1929-December 1937) (Box 25)
    - Works, articles, Correspondence, etc. (December 1937-Hov. 1838) (Box 25)
    - Industrial Life Insurance--Works;. Correspondence, Pamphlets, etc. (’33) (Box 25)
  - Insurance companies--Forms, rates, etc. (Jan & October 1925 etc.) (Box 25)
  - International Labor Office-- Correspondence (November 1925-5ept. 1926) (Box 26)
  - International Labor Organization: (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, monthly summary (April, ‘32-December ’41 (Box 26)
  - Magnusson, Leifur--Correspondence (February 1929-May 1939) (Box 26)
  - Inter-professional Assn.--Correspondence, bill draft, call (August '34-April '36) (Box 26)
  - Iowa--Correspondence (January 1929-June 1941) in 2 Folders. (Box 26)
  - Isaacs, Stanley H., friend of the Manhattan slum-dwellers--Correspondence, memorandum, organizations, etc. (September 1932-September 1941) (Box 26)
  - Italy--Regulations (guigno 1924-april 1925) (Box 26)
  - Japan--Correspondence, acts (October-November 1926) (Box 27)
  - Joint Com. on Unemployment (& Taxation)--Correspondence, etc. (October'31-June'34) (Box 27)
  - Joint Com. to Sponsor the Automobile Accident Compensation Plan-Articles, correspondence, etc. (March 1937-June 1938) (Box 27)
  - Kane, Francis Fisher, Attorney at Law, Philadelphia--Correspondence, (January 1933-February 1936) (Box 27)
  - Kansas--Correspondence (January 1930-November 1940) in 2 Folders. (Box 27)
  - Kelley, Nicholas, Treasurer of A.A.S.S. --Correspondence, (April 1930-Dec 1941) (Box 27)
  - Kentucky--Correspondence (April 1928-April 1937) (Box 27)
  - Labor, etc.--Newspapers, etc. (January 1925-0ct. 1928) (Box 28)
  - Lansburgh, Dr. Richard H., Univ. of Pa.--Correspondence, (May 1928-May 1930) (Box 28)
  - Larkin, Oliver W.--Correspondence (June-Ju1y 1934) (Box 28)
  - Leach, Agnes Brown--Correspondence (October 1929-March 1932) (Box 28)
  - League for Industrial Democracy--Corres., minutes, etc. (December ‘29-February ‘42) (Box 28)
  - Legislative questionnaire--Lists, clippings, etc. (September 1929-1930) (Box 28)
  - Lehman,, J. S. Circularization of pamph1ets--Correspondence, etc. (February. 1930-March 1934) (Box 28)
  - Leiserson, Dr. William. H.--Correspondence (February 1929-April 1938) (Box 28)
  - Louisiana--Correspondence, etc. (April 1930-oct. 1940) (Box 28)
  - Maine--Correspondence, etc. (March 1927-June 1941) (Box 29)
  - Massachusetts--Correspondence, etc. (October 1937-June 1929); (February 1932-February 1942) (Box 29)
  - MA:
    - Boston--Correspondence (January 1932-April 1942) (Box 29)
    - Saving Bank--Corres., statement (November 1926) (Box 29)
    - Wiesman, Margaret, Consumers' League --Correspondence, etc. (January ‘33-December ‘35; (January 1936-March'43) (Box 29)
  - Maryland--Correspondence (January 1929-Harch 1941) (Box 30)
  - Md. Baltimore--Correspondence (January 1934-December 1941) (Box 30)
  - Md. Imberman, A. A.--Correspondence (January 1935-September 1937) (Box 30)
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company--Correspondence, (March '37-March ‘42) (Box 30)
  - Michigan--Correspondence, etc. (September 1931-June 1935) in 2 Folders; (January 1937-April 1941) (Box 30)
  - Mich. Com. far Old Age Security--Lists or names (January 1933) (Box 30)
  - Mich:
    - Detroit--Correspondence (July 1938-February 1942) (Box 30)
    - Grand Rapids Com.--Correspondence (September 1931-January 1937) (Box 30)
    - Kalamazoo--Corres., list, etc. (December 1931-April 1934) (Box 30)
  - Middle age problem--Correspondence (November 1929-1942) (Box 31)
  - Minnesota--Correspondence (November 1928-July 1941) in 2 Folders. (Box 31)
  - Minn. Commission on the Aged--Pamphlets, Correspondence, synopsis (November 1925) (Box 31)
  - Mississippi-Correspondence (March 1931-November 1941) (Box 31)
  - Missouri: (Box 31)
  - Correspondence (February 1937-March 1939) (Box 31)
  - Poorhouses, poor farms: "Place of Horrors"-Inspection repts., etc. (1923-1933) (Box 31)
  - Mo.:
    - Com. for Old Age Security--Correspondence, etc. (April ‘32-September ‘33) (Box 31)
    - Leonard, Oscar--Correspondence (October 1954-December 1941) (Box 31)
  - Mo.: (Box 32)
    - Kansas City-Correspondence, etc. (September 1930-February 1939) (Box 32)
    - Russell, Meigs B.--Correspondence, lists & miscellaneous data (November 1931-April 1932) in 2 Folders. (Box 32)
    - St. Louis--Correspondence (January 1935-February 1942) (Box 32)
  - Montana--Correspondence (January 1925-December 1927); (November 1929-April 1938) (Box 32)
  - National Assn. of Manufactures--Clippings, Correspondence, etc. (April' 30-October '35) (Box 33)
  - (First-Third) National Conference on Old Are Security--Correspondence, proceedings, bills, etc. (April 1928-1931) in 6 Folders. (Box 33)
  - National Conference on Social Security--Correspondence, etc. (June 1932-November 1942) in 3 Folders. (Box 34)
  - Nationa1 Council of Jewish Women, Jersey City Section. Mahler, Benjamin (Minna)--Correspondence, (September 1930-May 1931) (Box 34)
  - National Industrial Recovery Act, Pamphlets, etc. (July-September 1933) (Box 34)
  - National Public Housing Conference. Alfred, Helen, Correspondence, etc. (September 1929-March 1934); (March 1937-April 1942) (Box 34)
  - Nebraska--Correspondence, (January 1958) (Box 34)
  - Netherlands--Regulations, Correspondence, etc. (October 1920-January 1927) (Box 34)
  - Neuberger, Dr. Otto--Corres., biographical sketch, etc. (January 1936-September 1942) (Box 34)
  - Nevada--Biennial rept. of the supt. old-age pensions 1923-1924 (1925) (Box 34)
  - New Hampshire--Corres., Legal information bul. (October 1930-December 1941) (Box 34)
  - NJ: (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, (January 1927-January 1942) (Box 35)
    - Lists, miscellaneous data (May-October 1931) (Box 35)
    - Press release (October 1929-December 1931) (Box 35)
    - Resolutions (February 1929-April 1931) (Box 35)
    - Speaking engagements--Correspondence, (May-September 1930) (Box 35)
    - Alloway, J. E., Trenton--Correspondence, etc (October 1932-November 1934) (Box 35)
    - Camden--Correspondence (October 1928-March 1931) (Box 35)
    - Consumers' League of N. J. Wiley, Katherine G. T.- General Correspondence, (November 1929-March 1934) (Box 35)
    - Assn. for Social Security--Correspondence, by-laws (November 1937-March 1938) (Box 35)
    - Council on Old Age Pensions: (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, statement, etc. (October 1930) (Box 35)
    - Correspondence w. Governor (December ’29-April ’31) (Box 35)
    - etc.--Contributions--Correspondence, etc. (April 1930-November) (Box 35)
    - Executive Com.--Minutes, agenda, lists, correspondence, etc. (February ‘30-May '3l) (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, etc. (January 1930-October 1932) in 2 Folders. (Box 35)
    - Board of Chosen Freeholders--Correspondence (December 1931) (Box 36)
    - Diocese of N. J. Weeles, Rev. Samuel G.--General Correspondence, (December 1929-November 1932) (Box 36)
    - Emil Franke1--Correspondence (January 1928-July 1940) (Box 36)
    - Federation of Labor. Reilley, Hugh V.--Correspondence (December 1929-June 1931) (Box 36)
    - Hasley, Florence--General Correspondence, (January 1930-February 1932) (Box 36)
    - Glover, Ralph--Correspondence, (October 1930-March 1931) (Box 36)
    - Jersey City--Correspondence, (May 1929-February 1933) (Box 36)
    - Leuper, Fred J.--Correspondence, (November 1929-January 1933) (Box 36)
    - Lewis R. D.--General Correspondence, (October 1930-August 1931) (Box 36)
    - New Brunswick--Correspondence, (October 1930-February 1931) (Box 36)
    - Newark--Correspondence, (November 1929-February 1934) (Box 36)
    - Paterson--Correspondence, (August 1930-February 1931) (Box 36)
    - Pension Survey Commission--Correspondence, reports. (September 1930-November 1931) (Box 36)
    - Permanent Conference--Correspondence, minutes, agenda, etc. (January-April 1930) (Box 36)
    - Plainfield--Correspondence, (December 1929-December 1930) (Box 36)
    - Trenton-general correspondence, (December 1929-November 1932) (Box 36)
    - Trenton. Ellis, William J.--Correspondence, (January 1931-0ct. 1941) (Box 36)
    - Women's Republican Club of N.J.--Correspondence, (August '30-January'3l) (Box 36)
  - New Mexico--Correspondence, (September 1934-June 1958) (Box 37)
  - New York (City)--Correspondence, (January 1930-October 1942) in 3 Folders. (Box 37)
  - N.Y.:
    - City Affairs Com.--Correspondence, minutes, etc. (December'37-December '42) (Box 37)
    - City Club--Correspondence, etc. (December 1936-April 1939) (Box 37)
    - N.Y. (City): (Box 37)
    - Congregational Education Society--Correspondence, (September ’31-Sep. '34) (Box 37)
    - Dept. of Welfare. Old Age Security Div., etc. --Correspondence, (May 1930-January 1943) (Box 37)
    - Shientag, Bernard L., Judge--Correspondence, (December ‘29-0ct. ‘50) (Box 37)
    - Welfare Council, Research Bureau--Private agencies (May ‘29) (Box 37)
  - N.Y. (State): (Box 38)
    - General Correspondence, (February 1938-September 1942) (Box 38)
    - Legislation--Old Age Assistance Act (Liberalization)--Correspondence, etc. (January 1937-March 1939) (Box 38)
    - Legislation--Old Age Pension bills--Signed by Governor (March-April 1930) (Box 38)